Hurry up! The flight leaves in four hours!
動作快，4小時後的班機
There could be traffic! The plane could leave early!
等叫到車可能都塞車了 飛機可能會提早起飛
In London,there could be a line at customs! Come on!
入境時可能會大排長龍，快點
Six-hour trip to London. That's a lot of Monica.
6小時的飛機，夠她念了
What have you got there?
那是什麼？
Condoms,dude.
保險套啊
Well,how come the writing is in spanish?
為什麼印西班牙文？
Don't read my condoms.
別看我的套子
Passport,check. Camera,check. Traveler's checks,check.
護照打勾，相機打勾 旅行支票打勾
-Who are you saying "check" to? -Myself.
你在叫誰打勾？ 我自己
For remembering to pack a thing.
記得一樣打一個勾
You do a good thing, you get a "check."
做一件好事就有個勾勾
Mom does it. I never realized it was weird.
這是媽的習慣，我沒想過很怪
My mom used to put her head in the oven.
我媽都把頭塞進烤箱裡
Actually,only the one time. But it's pretty weird.
其實只有一次，不過蠻怪的
Are you ready yet?
準備好了嗎？
-Got the tickets? -Right here. Check!
機票帶了嗎？ 在這裡，打勾
It's all London,baby!
去倫敦羅，寶貝
Here we go.
走吧
Got your passport?
護照呢？
Third drawer of my dresser. You don't want to lose that!
梳妝台第三個抽屜 弄丟就糟了
There it is!
快去
The One With Ross' Wedding
本集播出：「羅斯的婚禮」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
The vacuum's in my closet on the left side.
吸塵器在我的櫃子裡的左邊
Garbage bags are next to the refrigerator.
垃圾袋在冰箱旁邊
Rachel's gonna be here. Can't I just ask her?
瑞秋會在，我不能問她嗎？
Yeah,okay. Give that a try!
好啊，你問啊
-Let's do it. -Cheerio!
走羅 好耶
London,baby!
倫敦，寶貝
That's not gonna get annoying.
我絕對不會覺得煩
London,baby!
倫敦，寶貝
You know what? I was wrong.
你知道嗎？我錯了
We're all here. Let's get going!
人都到了，我們走吧
I want to go over and hug you...
我很想過去抱你...
...and wish you luck, but I can't get up.
...恭喜你 但是我起不來
-I'll come hug you. -Great,can you bring me the paper?
那我過去抱你 太好了，幫我拿報紙
-Have a great wedding. -Thanks.
快快樂樂的結婚吧 謝謝
Chandler,I want to hug you too!
錢德，我也想抱你
You might as well bring my book from your apartment.
順便去你家餐檯把我的書拿來
-So we're off. -Have fun!
我們要走了 玩得開心點
-I can't believe you won't be there. -I know.
你居然不能去 是啊
Come. Why don't you come?
去嘛，你為什麼不能去？
To London. Please? It would mean so much to me.
去嘛，一起去，我會很高興
I gotta work. I'm sorry.
我要忙，對不起
Why can't you take a couple of days off?
為什麼不能請兩天假？
Because I can't. I told you.
我不行，我說過了
This is my wedding.
這是我的婚禮
Now we are late. Let's go,let's go!
真的來不及了，走走走
Fine,you'll watch it on video when we get back.
好吧，回來再讓你看錄影帶
Here you go,Phoebe! Phoe-bo! Phoo-ba-la!
菲比，你的書書，蘇蘇 謝謝
You!
乖
Let's go!
走吧
Bye,Pheebs!
菲比再見 再見
London,baby!
倫敦，寶貝
Oh,God!
天哪
Do you need a hug?
你要抱抱嗎？
You don't have to bring me anything.
你不必拿東西給我
Chandler,do something!
錢德，做點動作
-Do something! -I am. I'm ignoring you.
做動作啊 我有啊，我在不理你
I'll be the on-camera guy.
好吧，我來上鏡頭
All right. First stop...
好，第一站
...Westminster Abbey.
西敏寺
What is that?
那是什麼？
That's London,baby!
倫敦啊，寶貝
All right,the hotel's here.
好，飯店在這裡…
Wait.
等一下
We want to go
不對，我們要去…
I know.
我知道了
I'm gonna have to go into the map.
我得進入地圖裡
If you see a little version of me in there,kill it!
要是裡面有個小錢德，殺了它
I got it.
我知道了
Here we go!
走吧
We're not gonna have to walk this way the entire time,are we?
我們不是要這樣逛大街吧？
Man,you made me lose it!
你害我又亂了啦
That was all before 10:00.
…那時候才10點
The caterer rang. It'll be Chicken Kiev,not Tarragon.
外燴打來說龍蒿雞換成基輔雞
Then the florist said there are no tulips.
然後花匠說沒有鬱金香了
And the cellist has carpal tunnel syndrome
然後大提琴手得了 手腕隧道症候群…
Emily,honey. Okay?
艾蜜莉，親愛的，好嗎？
Well,up yours too!
我也去你的
-What? -Oh,that's not what it means.
什麼？ 不是那個意思？
-No! That's "time out." -Sorry.
不，這是暫停的意思 對不起
Sweetie,relax. Everything will be great,okay?
放輕鬆，一切都會很美好
Come on,come on.
走吧
Chicken Kiev?
基輔雞？
Doesn't that sound delicious at the last minute?
臨時能有這道菜不錯吧？
Salmon would be more elegant than chicken.
是啊，但鮭魚會比雞肉高雅
And you wouldn't worry about the salmonella.
也不必擔心沙門氏菌 （沙門音同鮭魚）
But of course...
不過...
...with salmon you would have to worry about the chicknella.
...鮭魚也可能有雞門氏菌
I can't wait to see where you're getting married.
真想趕快看到婚禮場地
It's beautiful. Her parents got married here.
也對，那裡很美 她父母就在那裡結婚
I can't believe they're tearing it down.
它居然要被拆了
It's really the most lovely building. It's over
你絕對沒看過那麼美的房子 就在…
Oh,my God!
天哪
It's nice.
還不錯
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
What are we going to do?
怎麼會這樣？怎麼辦？
Everything's gonna be all right.
放心，不會有問題的
How's it gonna be all right?
怎麼會沒問題？
I see that.
說得也是
I talked to a guy, and I found out what happened.
我跟一個人問到了
They tore it down early.
怎麼回事？ 提前進行拆除
All right!
漂亮
Westminster Abbey.
西敏寺
Hands down,best abbey I ever seen.
絕對是我見過最美的寺
What do you think of the Abbey?
你覺得西敏寺如何？
It's great! They're thinking of changing the name.
很宏偉，他們正打算改名
-To what? -To "Put the Camera Away"!
改成什麼？ 改成「攝影機收起來」
Man,you are Westminster Crabby.
你真是西敏之狼
Don't worry,you'll find some place to get married.
放心，你們會找到場地的
Sorry. Lucky this dress is red.
抱歉，幸好紅色沾血看不見
We can't find another place.
不可能找得到場地
Then we can't have the wedding.
婚結不成了
I've ordered chicken,and salad, and cake for a 150.
我訂了一百五十人份的雞肉 沙拉和蛋糕
What should be the most wonderfull day of my life...
一生中最快樂的日子
...is rapidly turning into just Sunday with a spectacular amount of food.
變成被食物淹死的星期天
You're gonna find a place.
你們會找到場地的
But even if,God forbid,you didn't, so you postpone the wedding.
就算找不到，那就延期嘛
Is that really so bad?
有那麼糟糕嗎？
Think about it. You could take all the time your needed to get everything that you want.
你想想，你可以籌備得很完整
You could have tulips. You could have salmon.
你可以訂到鬱金香…和鮭魚
Salmon.
鮭魚喔
I suppose it wouldn't be the end of the world.
延期確實死不了
Oh,thank you.
謝謝你
Look,either way you're gonna get married. You're gonna be happy.
總之你都會結婚，都會幸福
My mom's gonna like you better than me.
我媽都會比較喜歡你
Oh,God. She has told you that already,didn't she?
天哪，她已經這麼說了對吧？
-Don't get up. What do you need? -Nothing.
別起來，你需要什麼？ 沒什麼
Come on. I'm here to take care of you.
我就是留下來照顧你的 你需要什麼？
Okay,I have a wedgie.
屁屁夾到內褲了
That is all you.
你自己解決
What do you want for lunch?
你中午想吃什麼？
I don't know.
我不知道
I guess we have to eat.
我們是得吃飯
Yeah,I do.
我一定要吃
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
I'm bummed the way I left things with Ross.
我應付羅斯的方式真差勁
I wish I didn't lie about work. He seemed so mad at me.
真後悔騙他說我要工作 他好像很氣我
Don't be so hard on yourself. If I was still in love with some
別太苛責自己 要是我還愛的人要結婚…
Still in love with?
還愛？ 是啊
I'm not in love with Ross.
我才沒有愛著羅斯
Good!
是沒有
Yeah,me neither.
很好，我也沒有
I'm not at the wedding, because he's my ex-boyfriend...
我不去是因為他是我的舊情人
...and that would be uncomfortable.
去了會很不自在
Not because I'm in love with him. I like Ross as much as anyone.
不是因為我還愛他 我跟大家一樣喜歡羅斯
Clearly,I have feelings for him, but they don't mean love.
我對他的確有感情 但那不是愛
I mean,do I still have loving feelings for Ross? Yeah!
我對羅斯還有愛的感覺嗎？有
I have continuing feelings of love.
我一直都有
But that doesn't mean I'm still in love with him.
但那並不表示我還愛著他
I have sexual feelings for him, but I do love him.
我對他還有「性」趣 但我當然愛他
Oh,my God!
天哪
Why didn't you tell me?
你為什麼不告訴我？
-We thought you knew! -We?
我們以為你知道 我們？
We all know. We talk about it all the time.
對，我們都知道，還經常在聊
You all know? Does Ross know?
你們都知道？羅斯知道嗎？
No! Ross doesn't know anything.
不，羅斯什麼都不知道
And you didn't tell me!
你們居然沒告訴我
We thought you knew. It's so obvious!
我們以為你知道，那麼明顯
It would be like telling Monica:
告訴你等於告訴摩妮卡
"Hey,you like things clean."
「喂，你很愛乾淨喔」
Or,you know,"Hey,Joey,you're gay."
或是「喬伊，你是同志喔」
What?
什麼？
Oh,please,she's always got a broom in her hand.
拜託，她老是拿著掃把
What are you in the market for? Scarves,souvenir postcards....
想買什麼？有圍巾、明信片…
Check this out!
你看
That's the stuff! What do you think?
這個就對了，你覺得呢？
I won't need that "I'm with stupid" T-shirt anymore.
我不必買印著 「與笨蛋同行」的衣服了
Well,I like it. Here you go.
我喜歡，錢給你
You're not really buying that. Haven't you embarrassed me enough?
你不是來真的吧 你丟我的臉丟得還不夠嗎？
Oh,I embarrass you?
我丟你的臉？
How can I answer when I'm pretending I don't know you?
我假裝不認識你，無法回答
He's just jealous. All Londoners wear them.
他是在嫉妒，倫敦人都在戴
Really? Then how come no one here anywhere is wearing one?
是嗎？那這裡怎麼沒人戴？
They're all tourists.
他們都是觀光客
If you insist on wearing that in public...
如果你要當街戴著那頂帽子
...you're gonna spend the afternoon all by yourself.
下午你就自己去逛
If you make me choose between you and the hat,I choose the hat.
如果要在你和帽子之間做選擇 我選擇帽子
-Good choice. -Thanks.
夠英明 謝了
That's it! I'm out of here. I won't be embarrassed any more.
夠了，我要走了 我不想再丟臉了
How are you doing? Joey Tribbiani,America.
你好，喬伊崔比亞尼，美國人
I spoke to your dad, and you know what?
我跟你爸談過，你猜怎樣？
He thinks we can find a new hall.
他覺得可以另外找到場地
-We don't have to. -You found a place?
不必了 你找到地方了？
No,but Monica and I were talking...
沒有，但摩妮卡和我討論過
...and I was so upset about the hall being knocked down...
我為了禮堂被拆的事很煩
...and she suggested we put the wedding off for a bit.
結果她建議把婚期延後
She said what?
她說什麼？
If I won't be happy with somewhere we'd find in a day...
如果我不喜歡臨時找個地方
...we should postpone it.
我們就應該延期
Postpone it.
延期
Do you think Monica realizes how much our parents spent on this?
你覺得摩妮卡知道 我們爸媽花了多少錢嗎？
Do you think my sister's teeny, tiny,little brain comprehends...
你覺得我妹的小腦袋能理解
...that people took time out of their lives...
大家特地挪出時間
...to fly thousands of miles to be here?
大老遠飛來這裡嗎？
This isn't right.
這麼做是不對的
I realize that people are gonna be disappointed.
我知道大家會失望
But I'm sure they'll come back.
但他們下次一定會再來
I can't ask people to do that. Would you?
我不能叫人家這麼做，你會嗎
Don't you point your pants at me!
別拿你的褲子指著我
We have no choice.
我們別無選擇
Anywhere half-decent will have been booked.
像樣一點的場地一定沒空檔
Don't you understand? This is our wedding!
你不懂嗎？這是我們的婚禮
Postponing it is not an option. This is when we're getting married.
我只知道延期是不可能的 要結就現在結
-You're saying it's now or never? -I'm saying it's now.
意思是否則就不結羅？ 不，我是說現在就結
-Or? -There's no "or" in mine!
否則呢？ 我沒說否則
What is wrong with these pants?
這條褲子是怎麼搞的？
It's not the pants. It's you who's backwards.
不是褲子，是你本末倒置
If you don't understand how important this is to me...
要是你不懂這件事對我多重要
...perhaps we shouldn't marry at all!
或許我們根本不該結婚
Emily,no! Wait,stop! Emily,please
艾蜜莉，等一下，別走
Did shopping help you feel any better?
血拼完有舒服一點嗎？
Manhattan doesn't have enough stores.
曼哈頓的店不夠
I can help you get over him.
我可以幫你忘了他
You can?
真的？
I need you to bring me photos of Ross...
對，拿一張羅斯的照片
...and a small piece of chocolate...
一小片巧克力
...and a glass of tepid water.
和一杯溫水來
Is this where you throw stuff...
是不是要...
...in a bag with graveyard dirt and hang it from a north-facing tree?
...跟墓地的土裝在一起 掛在面北的樹上？
Only if you have the hiccups too.
要是你也在打嗝的話
The chocolate and water are for me. I didn't feel like getting up.
照片是給你的，其他是我要的 我只是不想起來
I'll show you a picture of Ross.
我給你看一張羅斯的照片
And you remember all the bad things about him.
你要去想他不好的地方
-Focus on his flaws. -I can do that.
專心想他的缺點 沒問題
I did that while we were going out.
我們交往時我就這樣
Before we start,I want to say, for the record,I love Ross.
好，首先我想先聲明 我愛羅斯
He's such a great guy.
他真的好棒
Close your eyes.
好，閉上眼睛
Imagine that you're with Ross.
想像你跟羅斯在一起
Imagine that you're kissing him.
想像你在親他
You're running your hands all over his body.
你的手在他的身上游移
You run your hands through his hair but
你的手撫弄他的頭髮
Gross! It's some kind of grease.
但是好惡！是某種油
I don't know.
我不曉得
His hair never bothered me that much.
他的頭髮沒那麼困擾我
It was more crunchy than it was greasy.
那應該算是硬而不是油
This will be harder than I thought.
好吧，難度比我想的還高
Let's try some aversion therapy.
試試厭惡療法好了
Look at the picture.
看著照片 好
How do you feel now?
現在覺得怎樣？
Well,I like you less.
我比較不喜歡你了
在英國玩也一樣難玩
Sorry.
抱歉
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have said you were embarrassing me.
我才抱歉 我不該說你丟我的臉
That wasn't cool.
那樣很過份
If it makes you feel any better, I've had a really lousy day.
如果你會高興一點 我今天過得很悲慘
Me too.
我也是
-Yeah? -No!
真的？ 才怪
I had the best day ever!
我玩得超過癮的
Dude,check this out!
你看
有你的這段就快轉，無聊死了
Tell my friend you like my hat.
告訴我朋友你喜歡我的帽子
-What's your friend's name? -Chandler.
好，你朋友叫什麼？ 錢德
Hi,Chandler.
錢德你好
-That's -That's Fergie,baby!
那不是… 那是佛姬，寶貝
Joey says you don't like his hat, but I think it's kind of dashing.
喬伊說你不喜歡他的帽子 但我覺得蠻時髦的
So I hear you're single now.
聽說你恢復單身了
- Yeah,I don't like the hat that much. -Okay.
我對帽子沒喜歡到那個程度
When did you? How?
你什麼時候… 怎麼會…
I was trying to get to Buckingham Palace.
我想去白金漢宮
So I'm in my map and
就進入地圖，然後…
I understand you had a talk with Emily.
聽說你和艾蜜莉談過
Yes,I did.
沒錯
And you are welcome.
不客氣
Am l?
是嗎？
Was it your idea to postpone the wedding?
是你提議把婚期延後的？
-I'm going to the bathroom. -Wait up!
我要上廁所 等我
Since you're the fix-it lady, here's a pickle:
既然你這麼會解決問題 問題來了
What do you do when the bride says she doesn't want the wedding at all?
當新娘說她不想結婚時 你怎麼辦？
She said that? Why?
她這麼說？ 對 為什麼？
I don't know. I said it was stupid to put off the wedding...
我不知道 我說為了禮堂被拆就延期很蠢
...and she,like,flipped out.
她就捉狂了
Oh,my God! You're even dumber than I am.
天哪，你比我還笨
Excuse me?
什麼？
How long have you been planning this wedding?
你籌備這次婚禮多久了？
I don't know. A month?
不曉得，1個月吧
Emily's probably been planning it since she was 5.
艾蜜莉可能從5歲就在計劃了
Ever since the first time she hung a pillowcase from her head.
從她第一次把枕頭套 披在頭上開始
That's what we did.
女生都這樣
We dreamed about the perfect wedding.
我們夢想辦一場完美的婚禮
In the perfect place.
在一個完美的場地
With the perfect four-tiered wedding cake.
有一個完美的四層結婚蛋糕
With the little people on top.
上面有小人偶
But the most important part...
但最重要的...
...is that we had the perfect guy...
...是有個完美的男人
...who understood just how important all that stuff was.
瞭解這一切對我們有多重要
I had no idea.
我都不知道
That pillowcase thing,I thought you were doing The Flying Nun.
我以為你披枕頭套 是在學「快樂的修女」
Sometimes we were.
有時候是啦
Come on.
別哭了
Help me figure out what to do.
幫我想想辦法
Pretty intense,huh?
場面蠻緊張的 是啊
I hope Ross didn't think we left because we were uncomfortable here.
希望羅斯不會以為 我們是怕尷尬才進廁所
I hope he did.
希望他就是這麼想的
I thought of a good flaw. Ross pops his gum.
我想到一個缺點了 羅斯吃口香糖會吹泡泡
Oh,right.
沒錯
-Wait a minute. I do that too. -I know,it drives me crazy.
等等，我也會 是啊，我超受不了的
I'll get it.
我來接
Pheebs,it's Joey.
菲比，我是喬伊
Hey,Joey!
喬伊
I saw someone that looks just like you on the subway.
我在地鐵看到一個很像你的人
I was going to say hi,then I figured he doesn't care he looks like you.
我正想打招呼 又想到他不會在乎他長得像你
That just cost me 4 bucks.
你講了我4塊錢了
I called to see how the chick and the duck are doing.
我打來問小雞小鴨好不好
They're having fun with Aunt Phoebe. Aunt Rachel hasn't been helpful.
它們跟菲比阿姨玩得很開心 瑞秋阿姨沒什麼用
So do you miss me?
你想我嗎？
Kind of,but I've been having too much fun.
有點，但我玩得太高興了
You're not homesick yet?
你還沒想家？
I don't think so.
沒有，應該沒有
Well,the seven of us miss you.
我們七個都很想你
-Who's seven? -Me,Rachel...
哪七個？ 我，瑞秋，
...the birds,the babies.
雞鴨，寶寶
The babies miss me?
寶寶也想我？
Of course they do,or I'm just really hungry.
當然想，不然就是我太餓了
Pizza guy's here!
披薩來了
You ordered pizza without me?
你們趁我不在叫披薩？
But we were thinking about you. We ordered the Joey Special.
對，但我們有想著你 我們點了歡樂（喬伊）套餐
Two pizzas?
兩個披薩？
-Gotta go! Talk to you later. -Wait!
對，我得掛了，再聊 等等
Where did you get it from?
你們叫哪一家的？
（歡樂酒店）
And they're always glad you came
他們永遠歡迎您的光臨
You want to be where you can see
要去就去一個
Your troubles are all the same
讓你看得開的地方
You want to be Where everybody knows your name
要去就去一個 大家都認識你的地方
Why have you brought me here?
你帶我來這裡幹什麼？
You'll see.
等著瞧
This wedding won't happen.
我們不會結婚了
Ross.
羅斯
But imagine a lot more lights...
好，但想像更多燈火
...and fewer bricks...
少一點磚瓦，
...and flowers and candles.
還有鮮花蠟燭
And the musicians can go over here.
樂隊可以擺在這裡
The chairs can face this way and
椅子可以朝這邊，然後…
You go.
你講
But if you don't love this, we'll do it any other place or time.
不過要是你不喜歡 我們就改時間改地點
Really,it's fine.
真的沒關係
Whatever you want.
你高興就好
It's perfect.
這樣很完美
And,I don't know,if it rains
我不知道，要是下雨…
Then we'll get wet.
那就淋濕吧
I don't even have a date.
我連男朋友都沒有
Do you remember where the duck food is?
菲比 怎樣？你記得飼料在哪裡嗎？
In the guys' apartment, under the sink. Why?
記得，在男生那邊的水槽下面 怎麼了？
Because I'm going to London.
因為我要去倫敦
What? What do you mean?
什麼？什麼叫你要去倫敦？
I have to tell Ross I love him.
我得告訴羅斯我愛他
Take care and don't have the babies till I get back.
保重，等我回來再生
But what about all the finding-his-flaws stuff we've been doing?
那我們想了半天他的缺點呢？
Yeah,that didn't work.
沒用
You can't go. Ross loves Emily.
你不能去，羅斯愛的是艾蜜莉
I know,but I have to tell him how I feel.
我知道 但我得告訴他我的感覺
He deserves all the information to make an informed decision.
他應該知道所有狀況 好做出知道狀況的決定
You're going because you hope he'll say:
才怪，你去是希望他說
"l love you too. Forget the British chippy."
「我也愛你」 「別理那個英國妹了」
You think he will?
你覺得他會嗎？
No,because he's in love with the British chippy!
不會，因為他愛那個英國妹
You're just gonna mess with his head and ruin his wedding.
你去了只會把他搞亂 毀了他的婚禮
It's too late! You missed your chance.
太遲了，你錯過機會了
I'm sorry. This must be hard.
抱歉，你一定很難受
But it's over.
但已經結束了
No,it's not over until someone says,"l do."
不，有人說「我願意」 才算結束
I do! I do!
我願意！我願意…
Like I can really chase you. I'm carrying a litter!
誰追得上你，我懷了一窩豬仔
The Waltham residence.
華森公館
Is this Emily's parents' house?
是艾蜜莉的父母家嗎？
This is the housekeeper speaking.
我是管家
And,by the way,that is not how one addresses a person on the telephone.
還有，小姐 講電話不能這樣講
First one identifies oneself...
先表明身份
...and then asks for the person with whom one wishes to speak.
再請你想找的人過來
What are you saying?
你在說什麼？
Now,let us try that again,shall we?
我們重來一次
No!
不！
Oh,my God!
天哪
-The Waltham residence. -Hello.
華森公館
This is Phoebe Buffay. I was wondering,please...
我是菲比布非，我是想麻煩你
...if it's not too much trouble,please...
如果不是很麻煩的話
...might I speak with Miss Emily Waltham,please?
我能和艾蜜莉華森小姐通話嗎
Miss Waltham is at the rehearsal dinner.
華森小姐去排練餐會了
And it is not polite to make fun of people. Goodbye.
嘲弄別人的口音是不禮貌的 再見
I'll be nice,I swear. Could you just give me the number for where they are?
不！我會有禮貌，我發誓 可以把現場的電話給我嗎？
I'm afraid I'm not at liberty to divulge that information.
我恐怕沒有權利洩露這項訊息
Somebody is on their way to ruin the wedding,and I have to warn somebody.
有人正要去破壞婚禮 我得警告他們
So if you don't give me that number, I'm gonna come over there...
你不給我號碼，我就殺到倫敦
...and I'm gonna kick your snooty ass all the way to New Gloukenshire!
把你一腳踹到新咕嚕肯夏去
Hello? Hello?
She knew I could kick her ass.
她知道我說到做到
-Hi,sweetheart. -Mom,Dad.
乖兒子 媽 爸
Sorry we're late.
抱歉遲到了
My fault. I insisted on riding the tube.
是我不好，我堅持要坐管子
Judy,the kids!
茱蒂，孩子都在
Jack,that's what they call the subway.
傑克，那是地鐵的俗稱
-I thought -Dad,we got it.
我以為… 爸，我們懂
Here comes my dad and stepmom.
我爸和繼母來了
Mr. and Mrs. Geller.
伯父伯母，
-This is Steven... -Hello,darling.
這是史帝芬…
...and Andrea Waltham.
和安瑞亞華森
Very nice to meet you.
幸會
Darling,the Gellers.
老婆，是蓋勒家的人
Darling,it's the Gellers.
老婆，是親家
She's very self-involved. I should never have married her.
她只想著自己，我不該娶她的
-It's the Gellers. -Where?
你說什麼？是蓋勒家的人 在哪裡？
That's one and that's another one.
那邊一個，那邊一個
Lovely to meet you.
很高興認識你們
Nice of you to offer to pay for half the wedding.
謝謝你們出一半的錢
The hell with tradition. We're happy to do it.
不客氣，去他的習俗 我們很樂意
We know how expensive weddings can be.
我們知道結個婚有多花錢
Besides,this may be the only wedding we get to throw.
而且以後可能就沒機會了
A joke that's funny in all countries.
真是個世界通行的笑話
Sir?
您要嗎？
-What's in it? -Goat cheese,watercress and pancetta.
裡面包什麼？ 羊酪、水田芥和培根
That's not food.
這能吃嗎？
Everything's different here. I want to go home.
這裡的東西都不一樣 我想回家
I miss my family,the coffeehouse.
我想念我的家人，想念咖啡館
I can't even remember what Phoebe looks like!
我連菲比的長相都不記得了
It's been three days.
我們才來3天
Okay,you're just homesick.
你只是想家了
Would you just try to relax and just enjoy yourself?
放輕鬆，好好玩就對了
You're different here too.
連你都變了
You're mean in England!
你在英國好壞
What the hell?
搞什麼？
What's up,Dad?
怎麼了？
This bill for my half of the wedding. It's insane.
我的這份帳單 太扯了
How can it be so much? The reception's at their house.
怎麼會這麼貴？ 請客是在家裡請
Flowers,liquor. Re-carpet first floor?
花，酒，一樓重鋪地毯？
New guest bath,landscaping.
新的客用浴室，造景
I'm paying to remodel this guy's house.
我在出錢讓他們裝修
I'm gonna give that son of a bitch a piece of my mind.
我要把那個混蛋罵一頓
Please.
爸，別激動
I don't want anything to upset Emily tonight.
我不想讓艾蜜莉不開心
She's had a hard enough couple of days as it is.
她這兩天已經夠心煩了
Here. Let me go talk to him.
給我，我去跟他談
You tell him no one takes advantage of the Gellers.
告訴他誰也別想占蓋勒家便宜
Sometimes I forget how powerful you can be.
傑克 有時候我都忘了你多有氣概
And I'm gonna go get drunk.
我要去喝個爛醉
-Hello. -Hello.
你好 你好
When is your next flight to London?
下一班飛倫敦的班機？
There's one leaving in 30 minutes.
半小時後有一班
And I do have one seat left.
還剩一個空位
Thank you,thank you.
謝謝你
The last-minute fare on this ticket is $2700.
臨時票的價錢是2700元
Huh. How about 600?
賣我6百如何？
-Sorry. -How about 600 and these earrings?
抱歉 6百再加這對耳環
They prefer it if I don't barter.
公司是覺得最好不要
I don't think I have enough left on my credit card.
我的信用卡額度不夠
You can split it with another card.
你可以分兩張刷
How about five?
五張可以嗎？
Thank you.
謝謝
I'm just going to need to see your passport.
請出示護照
I don't have it,but I can tell you exactly where it is on my nightstand.
我沒帶，不過我可以告訴你 它就在我的床頭櫃上
You know what? I have my driver's license.
這樣吧，我有駕照
And I have a 20.
還有一張20元鈔票
Face it. My father is not going to pay for the built-in barbecue.
我爸不會付內建烤爐的錢
And believe me,you can kiss your gazebo goodbye.
還有，涼亭也免談
I might be able to get you the new lawn.
我或許可以爭取到新草皮
Then you have to give us the lawn ornaments.
那也得給草坪的裝飾品
I go back there with lawn ornaments, he'll laugh in my face.
我要是答應會被我爸笑死
This is ridiculous. I mean,we had an agreement.
太扯了，大家都說好了
Will you say something,Steven?
史帝芬，你說句話好嗎？
Don't take that tone with me.
別對我這麼不客氣
All right,you can.
好吧，隨你
Thank God!
菲比 謝天謝地
You changed your mind.
你改變心意了
You probably want to be alone, you don't want to talk about it.
你現在或許想靜一靜
You're doing the right thing.
沒關係，你這麼做是對的
Where are you going?
再見 等等，你要去哪裡？
What are you doing? No,wait.
你又想幹什麼？等等
Why am I always pregnant when she does that?
為什麼每次她這樣 我都在懷孕
I'd like to make a toast to Ross and Emily.
我想敬羅斯和艾蜜莉一杯
My big toast is tomorrow.
我明天會正式敬酒
This is kind of my little toast, or Melba toast,if you will.
今天是非正式敬酒 也就是隨便敬敬
Okay.
好，
I've known Ross for a long time. I knew him when he was with his first girlfriend.
我跟羅斯認識很久了 他第一次交女朋友我都知道
I thought things were going to work out for him,until the day he over-inflated her.
我以為他們很順利 直到那天他替她「充氣」
Oh,dear God!
天哪
Hello,Waltham lnteriors.
華森府邸
Mrs. Waltham.
華森太太
I need to speak with one of the best men or Ross' sister,Monica.
我想找羅斯的伴郎之一或妹妹摩尼卡
-Who is this? -Phoebe,one of Ross' best friends.
你是誰？我是菲比布非 羅斯最要好的朋友之一
How did you get this number?
你怎麼知道這個號碼？
I got it from your maid. She's a bitch,but I wore her down.
跟你的女傭問的 她很賤，但我比她更賤
If you're one of Ross' best friends, why aren't you here?
既然是羅斯的朋友怎麼沒來？
I can't fly. I'm having my brother's babies.
我不能坐飛機 我懷了我弟的孩子
Am I on the radio?
是廣播節目嗎？
Can I talk to one of them? It's important.
不是 我可以找他們嗎？我有要緊事
I'm bored of you now. I'm going to cut you off.
我對你沒興趣了，我要掛了
Oh,okay,I'm going to have to kick her ass too.
我也要踹她
We're excited that Ross and Emily are getting married at Montgomery Hall.
很高興羅斯和艾蜜莉 要在蒙哥馬利禮堂結婚
To think,my friend getting married in Monty Hall.
我朋友要在「蒙帝霍爾」結婚 （霍爾字同禮堂）
Come on,Monty Hall!
拜託，蒙帝霍爾啊
Let's Make a Deal. Come on,you people!
「大家來挑戰」主持人啊 笑一下吧
All right,forget it. Congratulations,Ross and Emily.
算了，恭喜 羅斯和艾蜜莉
Best man number two,Joey Tribbiani.
伴郎二號，喬伊崔比亞尼
I'm not good with the jokes like Chandler here.
我沒錢德那麼會說笑話
Congratulations to the happy couple.
我只想說恭喜這對幸福的新人
I first met Ross in this coffeehouse back home.
我在我家附近咖啡館認識羅斯
Home.
家
New York City.
紐約市…
Where everybody knows my name.
在那裡大家都認識我
Anyway...
總之...
...I love you guys.
我愛你們
But not as much as I love America.
但是我更愛美國
Can we please go home now?
我們回家了好不好？
Are you going home?
你要回去了？
I was hoping to get to know you better.
我正想進一步瞭解你
I'm not going anywhere,sweetheart.
美人，我哪兒也不去
I was laughing.
我有笑啊
Out loud?
有笑出聲嗎？
I didn't want everyone to think I was stupid.
我不想讓別人覺得我很白癡
So how are you?
你好嗎？
My mother's driving me crazy. But Ross is getting married. I'm happy.
我媽快把我逼瘋了 但是我很替羅斯高興
I'm not going to let anything spoil that.
我不會讓任何人掃我的興
I just want to say that Ross is a wonderful young man.
我只想說羅斯真是個好青年
Thanks. We like him.
謝謝，我們都喜歡他
My God! You must have been a teenager when you had him.
天哪，你生他時一定才十幾歲
There's no way in hell I'm paying for it.
我絕對不會付錢
Look,we're down to just one point.
好，我只問一件事
Could we please just settle it after the wedding?
能不能婚禮後再解決？
Fine,but I'm not paying for your wine cellar...
好，但我絕不付酒窖的錢
...you thieving, would-be-speaking- German-if-it-weren't-for-us, cheap little man!
靠美國才沒被德國殖民的小人
The guy was hammered. There's no way you look like Ross' mother.
那傢伙醉昏了 你怎麼可能像羅斯的媽
-Then why would he say it? -Because he's crazy!
那他為何會認錯？ 因為他瘋了
He came up to me earlier and thanked me for my very moving performance in Titanic.
之前他還謝謝我 在「鐵達尼號」裡演得很棒
My mother's right. I'll never get married.
我媽說得對，我嫁不出去了
You know what,that is
這麼說就…
Who wouldn't want you?
誰不想要你？
Please! I'm a single mom with a 30-year-old son.
拜託 我是個兒子30歲的單親媽媽
-Hi,I'm back. Listen,I need to -Hello.
我回來了，聽著，我得… 你好
Hello. I need to get on that 11:00 flight.
你好，我得趕11點那班飛機
I'm afraid that plane's already pulled away from the gate.
那架班機已經起飛了
You're going to have to call that plane and tell them to swing around and pick me up.
你得叫他們掉頭回來接我
-Can't do that. -Sure,you know what?
我不能那麼做
We'll just tell them that there was, like, a problem with, like, the engine.
當然可以，就說引擎有問題
I'm afraid I'm going to have to ask you to step aside, miss.
我恐怕得請你讓開
Look,if I don't get to London he is gonna marry that other girl.
我不趕去倫敦，他會娶別人
Can't imagine why.
真不懂是為什麼
All right. You know what?
你知道嗎？
I am not leaving here until you call that plane back.
你不把架飛機叫回來我就不走
（暫停服務）
I'm getting married today!
我今天要結婚了
Morning.
早啊，羅斯
-I'm getting married today! -Yeah,you are.
我今天要結婚了
Do you think he knew I was here?
你覺得他有發現嗎？
-Excuse me. -Yeah.
抱歉 是
If you're going to do that throughout the flight,tell me now...
要是你打算一路敲打到倫敦 現在就說
...so that I can take a sedative.
我好吃鎮靜劑
Or perhaps slip you one.
或是給你一顆
I'm sorry. I'm very sorry. Sorry.
對不起，非常抱歉
It's just,I'm kind of excited.
我只是有點興奮
I'm going to London...
我要去倫敦...
...to tell this guy that I love him.
...告訴一個人我愛他
Well,I've never done that with you before.
我沒跟你做過這檔事
是沒有
So how are you?
你怎樣？
You okay?
還好嗎？
Yeah. Yeah. You?
很好，你呢？
Oh,yes. Yes.
很好…
You?
你呢？
We did you.
我們問過你了
Well....
-I better get going. -Absolutely.
我該走了 好，當然
Could you not look?
你能不能不要看？
I don't want to look.
我不想看
Where the hell have you been?
你死哪去了？
I spent the night out. I met this cute bridesmaid. She is so...
我沒回來睡 我認識了可愛的伴娘，她好…
I don't want to hear it!
我不想聽
Pheebs,you know you're still my number-one girl.
菲比，我最喜歡的還是你
No. No. We have an emergency. Rachel's coming to London.
不，出事了，瑞秋跑去倫敦了
Great!
太好了
No,it's not great. She's coming to tell Ross that she loves him.
一點也不好 她要去告訴羅斯她愛他
But he loves Emily.
但是羅斯愛艾蜜莉
I know that!
我知道
You have to stop her. She's going to ruin the wedding.
你得阻止她，她會破壞婚禮
Okay.
好
-All right,so -Hold on,hold on.
所以… 等等
Rachel coming.
瑞秋來了
Do...
想…
...something.
...辦法
I've done my part,okay?
我該做的都做了
It's your responsibility now. The burden is off me.
現在該你負責 我卸下這個責任了
-Right? -Right.
對吧？ 對
So tell me about this girl.
說說這個伴娘吧
And so then I realized, all the stuff that I had been doing...
結果我發現我的一切舉動
...proposing to Joshua,lying to Ross about why I couldn't come to the wedding...
向約書亞求婚、騙說我要忙
-...was all just a way -Oh,oh,oh,oh!
都只是一種…
I'm sorry,can I interrupt?
抱歉，可以打個岔嗎？
I just want to say that you are a horrible, horrible person.
你真是個很糟糕，很糟糕的人
Pardon me?
你說什麼？
You say you love this man,and yet you're about to ruin the happiest day of his life.
你說你愛這個人 卻要去破壞他的大喜之日
I'm afraid I have to agree with your friend Pheebs.
我不得不同意你朋友菲比的話
This is a terrible, terrible plan.
這是個很差勁，很差勁的打算
-But he has to know how I feel. -But why?
但他必須知道我的感受 為什麼？
He loves this Emily person. No good can come of this.
他愛這個艾蜜莉 這麼做絕對沒好處
-Well,I think you're wrong. -Oh,no.
我覺得你錯了 才怪
Well,he doesn't really love her. It's just a rebound thing from me.
他並非真的愛她 只是失去我需要寄托
-You'll see. -Fortunately I won't.
你等著瞧 幸好我看不到
And by the way,it seems to be perfectly clear that you were on a break.
還有，你們當時顯然是分手了
Do something.
想辦法
Something.
辦法
-Have you seen Monica? -I'm not seeing Monica!
你有看見摩妮卡嗎？ 我沒有在跟摩妮卡交往
-What? -What?
什麼？ 啥？
We gotta find her. Rachel's coming to tell Ross she loves him.
我們得找到她 菲比說瑞秋要來向羅斯表白
-Oh,my God! -I know. Do you know where Monica is?
天哪 沒錯，所以要找到摩妮卡 你知道她在哪裡嗎？
No. What's with the third degree? Why not just shine a light in my eyes?
不知道！你在逼問什麼？ 乾脆拿燈照我的眼睛算了
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
It's like a fairyland.
跟仙境一樣
I know. It's horrible,isn't it?
是啊，很恐怖吧？
I love it. I only hope my wedding looks this good.
我好喜歡 希望我的婚禮也能這麼美
-I just hope -You can let some of them go by.
我覺得… 有些話就別接了
Start looking out for Rachel.
開始注意瑞秋
I'll cover the front door. You watch that big hole.
我守前門 你守後面那個大洞
And I got Chandler covering Ross.
羅斯那裡有錢德顧著
Why would I care where Chandler is?
我幹嘛管錢德在哪裡？
You know...
...sometimes I don't even like Chandler.
有的時候我根本不喜歡錢德
Okay.
好
I do.
我願意…
我願意
-You're right. It's the second one. -Right?
沒錯，第二個比較好 是嗎？
Hello,Joey.
喬伊
Hey,Felicity.
費麗西蒂
I thought about you all day.
我整天都在想你 是嗎？
Talk New York to me again.
再跟我講講紐約的事
Forget about it.
別管紐約了
How you doing?
你好嗎？
There's nothing to discuss. We're not paying for your wine cellar.
沒什麼好談的 我們不會付酒窖的錢
You have to meet me in the middle here.
你們總得折衷一下
My foot's gonna meet the middle of your ass.
你再囉唆我就踹你的屁眼
-What's going on? -Everything's under control.
怎麼了？ 沒事，一切都在掌握中
You want a piece of me,sir? Is that what you're saying?
你想幹架？你是這個意思嗎？
That's it! Parents! Parents! Back away!
夠了，雙方家長，退後
This is our wedding day!
這是我們的大喜之日
From now on,everyone gets along.
你們給我好好相處
And if I hear one more word...
誰再多說一個字
...no grandchildren! That's right!
就別想抱孫子，沒錯
-Okay,okay. -Sorry,old boy.
知道了 抱歉
I could kill you with my thumb, you know.
我用大拇指就能扳倒你
What was all that about?
這是怎麼回事？
It was this disagreement over
只是一些費用上的…
My God! You look beautiful.
天哪，你真美
You're not meant to see me before the wedding. It's bad luck.
行禮前看到新娘會不吉利
I think we've had all the bad luck we're going to have.
我們的惡運應該都用完了
My God,Rachel!
天哪，瑞秋
You're here. I can't believe it.
你來了，我真不敢相信
What happened? Why are you here?
你怎麼跑來了？
I just came to
我只是來…
I just needed to tell you...
我只是得告訴你…
...congratulations.
恭喜你
Hello,Waltham lnteriors.
華森府邸
Mrs. Waltham? It's Phoebe.
華森太太嗎？又是我，菲比
Why?
怎麼又是你？
Can I talk to one of the best men? This is going to be the last time.
我可以跟伴郎之一說話嗎？ 我保證這是最後一次
There's a girl on the phone for you.
有個女生找你
Great!
真好
It's Phoebe.
喬伊，是菲比
Did you stop Rachel?
你有堵到瑞秋嗎？
No,but it's okay. She just came in and gave him a hug. That's it.
沒有，但沒事 她只有抱抱他而已
-Nothing got ruined? -No.
沒有破壞什麼？ 沒有
That's so great!
太好了
So,what's going on now?
現在怎麼樣了？
I'm walking down the aisle.
我正在走紅毯
Still walking.
還在走
I'm about to pass the bridesmaid I hooked up with last night.
我正要經過昨晚那個伴娘面前
Hey.
I just told her "hey."
我剛跟她說嗨
I'm at the front with Ross.
我跟羅斯站在一起了
It's Phoebe!
是菲比
He looks pretty mad.
他看起來很不爽
I better go.
我得掛了
Wait! Hold it up so I can listen.
等一下！拿著讓我聽
-What we did last night was -Stupid.
昨晚的事真是… 愚蠢
Totally crazy, stupid.
既誇張又愚蠢
What were we thinking?
我們在想什麼？
I'm coming over tonight though, right?
我晚上去找你，好嗎？
Definitely.
當然好
Friends,family...
各位親朋好友
...we are gathered to celebrate...
我們今天齊聚一堂
...the joyous union of Ross and Emily.
慶祝羅斯與艾蜜莉締結良緣
May the happiness of today...
願今朝的幸福...
...be with them always.
...永遠與他們同在
Now,Emily,repeat after me.
艾蜜莉，跟我複述
-l,Emily... -l,Emily...
我，艾蜜莉…
-...take thee,Ross... -...take thee,Ross....
嫁給你，羅斯…
...as my lawfully wedded husband, in sickness and in health...
做我合法的丈夫 無論貧病...
...till death parts us.
至死不渝
As my lawfully wedded husband, in sickness and in health...
做我合法的丈夫 無論貧病...
...until death parts us.
至死不渝
Now,Ross.
羅斯
Repeat after me.
跟我複述
I,Ross...
我，羅斯…
...take thee,Emily...
迎娶你，艾蜜莉…
...take thee,Rachel
迎娶你，瑞秋…
Emily.
艾蜜莉
Shall I go on?
還要繼續嗎？
"Mother,Mother,Pizza,Pizza," take one.
第一次…
Oh,the band's ready? We gotta do what the band says,right?
樂隊準備好了？ 樂隊怎麼說我就怎麼做
I don't care about the stupid band!
我才懶得管樂隊呢
-Well,it's getting late. -Here we go.
咱們去上床
Actually,you guys mind staying here with me for a while?
你們可以陪我一下嗎？
You know,we gotta get up early and catch the plane to New York.
我們早上要趕飛機
Yeah,it's a very large plane.
對，那架飛機很大
Why,what's the matter?
怎麼了？